Emergency Committee on the Transportation Crisis 036
People's Archive, MLK Library
- Series 5: Printed Matter, 1967-1981
  - Rooney, Angela, "Freeways Urban Invaders", October 1971 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Scientific American, Letters to the editor, September 1969 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Smithsonian, To stop highways some citizens take to the streets, April 1972 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Tekniska Hogskolan, 1973 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Transportation Planning in D.C., 1955-1965, March 1966 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Urban Design and Development Corporation, "Georgetown Waterfront Feasibility Study", December 1970 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Urbanaction, "Urban Transportation Crisis", Spring, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - U.S. Catholic and Jubilee, January 1969 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, "The Civil Rights Implications of Suburban Freeway Construction", August, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - U.S. Comptroller General "Problems Associated With Location and Design of Segments of the Interstate Highway System in Major Metropolitan Areas", August, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - U.S. Congress, "Our American Government", 1969 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, "Report for Consultation on the D.C. National Capital Interstate Air Quality Control Region", July 1968 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Victor Gruen Associates, "Anacostia Urban Code", October 1967 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, "Metro Memo", 1971-1975 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, "Metro Memo", 1971-1975 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, "Metro Memo", 1971-1975 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, "Notice of Metrobus Public Hearing," Nos. 32-38, 1974-1975 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Printed Materials, General, 1960-1970 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Printed Materials, General, 1960-1970 (Box 35, Folder 2)
- Series 6: Clippings and Press Materials, 1968-1979
  This series contains clippings, press releases, and related legislative items which focus primarily on freeway construction and transportation issues in the Nation. Clippings are not arranged. Press releases and related materials are arranged chronologically after the clippings.
  - Clippings, 1968-1979 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Clippings (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Clippings (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Clippings (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Clippings (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Clippings (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Clippings (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1968-1979 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Clippings (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Clippings (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1968-1979 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Clippings (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Clippings (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Clippings (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Loose Clippings, 1968-1979 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Loose Clippings, 1968-1979 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Loose Clippings, 1968-1979 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Loose Clippings, 1968-1979 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Press releases and legislative materials, 1965-1971 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Press releases and legislative materials, 1965-1971 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Press releases and legislative materials, 1965-1971 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Press releases and legislative materials, 1965-1971 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Press releases and legislative materials, 1965-1971 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Press releases and legislative materials, 1965-1971 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Press releases and legislative materials, 1965-1971 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Press releases and legislative materials, 1965-1971 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Press releases and legislative materials, 1965-1971 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Press releases and legislative materials, 19665-1971 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Press releases and legislative materials, 1965-1971 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Press releases and legislative materials, 1965-1971 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Press releases and legislative materials, 1965-1971 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Press releases and legislative materials, 1965-1971 (Box 40, Folder 14)
- Series 7: Flyers, 1969-1973; 1987-89
  This series contains flyers about rallies, demonstrations, meetings, and lobbying activities sponsored by ECTC and other organizations involved in the Washington metro area freeway fight. Of significance are flyers about the fight to save the Three Sisters Bridge, rallies to protest government-confiscated homes on 10th and Franklin Streets, N.E., and public events expressing opposition to the North-Central Freeway. Other flyers cover issues about which ECTC was interested, including the environment, statehood, home rule, poverty, and racial discrimination.
  - Flyers, 1969-1973 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Flyers, 1969-1973 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Flyers, 1969-1973 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Flyers, 1969-1973 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Flyers, 1969-1973 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Flyers, 1969-1973 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Flyers, Undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Flyers - Statehood, 1987-1989 (Box 41, Folder 8)
- Series 8: Membership, 1967; Undated
  Included in this series is a guest book of signatures from an unidentified ECTC event, blank membership cards for the Brookland Neighborhood Association (1967), and 3x5 cards with handwritten information on activist organizations of interest to ECTC.
  - Attendance lists, Undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Blank Brookland Neighborhood Association membership cards, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Organizational information cards, Undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
- Series 9: Photographs and Memorabilia, 1968-1979
  The few photographs appearing in this collection are contained in this series. The series also contains ECTC's bumper sticker "Save Don't Pave," a statehood flag, and other memorabilia.
  - Negative for "White Men's Roads Thru Black Man's Homes" poster, Undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, 1968-1979 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, 1968-1979 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, 1968-1979 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 1968-1979 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, 1968-1979 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, Undated (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Kenneth Kennedy memorial program, 1974 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Bumper stickers, Undated (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Letterhead, Undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Martin Luther King Memorial Arts Festival pin, Undated (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Statehood flag, Undated (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - "Arlington Coalition on Transportation", February 1972 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - "Arlington Freeway and Parkway Routes", Undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - "Initiative Measure No. 274 blank petition: Reduce [Washington] State Gas Tax", July 1972 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - "Transportation Alternative Study", Undated (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Fortune - "How the Interstate Changed The Fact of the Nation" by Juan Cameron", July 1971 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - National Capital Planning Commission - "Shoreline Acquisition and Development Policies and Programs", 1976 (Box 45, Folder 6)
- Series 10: Architectural Drawings and Maps, 1967-1974
  - Mass Transportation Plan, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Recommended Freeway and Parkway, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Major Transportation Plan, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Takoma Park Metro area sketch (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Rhode Island Ave. Station scaled drawing, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Comprehensive Plan for the National Capitol area General Land Use Objectives: 1970/1985 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Ft. Totten area drawing (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Michigan Ave. Station sketch (by METRO) (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Michigan Ave. Station "Working Plan (by Metro)", 1969 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Ft. Totten Metro sketch (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Brookland Station sketch (by WMATA), 1972 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Problem objectives diagram 1 1967/1985 with public involvement program priories key (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - General Land Use Objectives Map 1967/1985 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Transportation diagram 2: 1967/1985 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Metro minutes station to station chart (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - UNECC map of homes & road construction (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Brookland & Ft. Totten Metro Area Site Plan (by Kronstadt et al.) (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Taylor and Hawaii Streets. commercial study (for Horning Brothers), 1978 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - Taylor and Hawaii Streets. drawing of convenience stores (for Horning Brothers) (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Scaled drawing of roads (Box 46, Folder 20)
  - Trinity College Phasing Plan, 1978 (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - Takoma Park Metro sketch, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 22)
  - Takoma Park Metro sketch (with colored markings), 1971 (Box 46, Folder 22a)
  - Brookland Station scaled drawing (Box 46, Folder 23)
  - Michigan Ave. Station scaled drawing (by D.C. DOT) (Box 46, Folder 24)
  - Michigan Ave. Station scaled drawing(by D.C. DOT) (Box 46, Folder 25)
  - Rhode Island Ave. Station Central Freeway (Box 46, Folder 26)
  - Rapid rail transit map modified (by NCTA Office of Planning) (Box 46, Folder 27)
  - Rapid rail transit map proposed (by WMATA), 1967 (Box 46, Folder 28)
  - D.C. Dept. of Highways Major Highway projects map, 1967 (Box 46, Folder 29)
  - North central freeway D.C. and Montgomery counties, 1967 (Box 46, Folder 30)
  - Brookland Station General Plans "Working Paper" (by H. Weese et al.), 1972 (Box 46, Folder 31)
  - Brookland Station General Plans Preliminary (by H. Weese et al.), 1972 (Box 46, Folder 31)
  - Brookland Station Redesign Concept, 1972 (Box 46, Folder 32)
  - Brookland Station Redesign System-Study 4 (Box 46, Folder 33)
  - Rhode Island Ave. Station diagram (Box 46, Folder 34)
  - Rhode Island Ave. Station diagram, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 35)
  - Brookland Area Coordinating Council 1985 proposal, 1967 (Box 46, Folder 36)
  - Catholic University area scaled drawing (Box 46, Folder 37)
  - D.C. freeway parking routes (Box 46, Folder 38)
  - Metro system map, 1970 (Box 46, Folder 39)
  - North central freeway plat map (Box 46, Folder 40)
  - Summary comparison of alternatives, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 41)
  - Summary of Recommended Corridor Design Concepts, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 42)
  - Trinity College Plans (Box 46, Folder 43)
  - The Heights Varnum & Taylor Streets (Box 46, Folder 44)
  - D.C. Hospital Center & Veterans Hospital utility, water & sewer plants (Box 46, Folder 45)
  - The Heights Flood Plans, 1978 (Box 46, Folder 47)
  - Michigan Avenue Metro depressed tracks (1 of 2), 1971 (Box 46, Folder 48)
  - Michigan Avenue Metro depressed tracks (2 of 2), 1971 (Box 46, Folder 49)
  - Rhode Island Avenue Station, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 49)
  - D.C. Office of Planning plat Map w/freeway construction outlined, 1973 (Box 46, Folder 51)
  - D.C. Dept. of Highways Restudy of Freeway System, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 52)
  - Takoma Park Metro scaled drawing, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 53)
  - Preliminary Master Plan Washington Metro Area, 1967 (Box 46, Folder 54)
  - Marist Seminary Prelim. grading & topographic survey (2 drawings), 1974 (Box 46, Folder 55)
  - Preliminary Master Plan of Highways P.G. County, 1967 (Box 46, Folder 56)
  - Taylor tract site plan, 1974 (Box 46, Folder 57)
  - Rhode Island Ave. Station scaled drawing, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 58)
  - NCPC freeway map (Box 46, Folder 59)
  - Preliminary Master Plan of Highways Montgomery City, 1967 (Box 46, Folder 60)
  - Ft. Totten Metro scaled drawing, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 61)
  - North central freeway Montgomery Counties; Supp. Study, D.C. (Box 46, Folder 62)
  - Poster-Freeway Cancer Hits D.C. North Central Freeway (Box 46, Folder 63)
  - "Freeway Cancer Hits D.C." Poster (Box 46, Folder 63)
  - WMATA regional metro system adopted, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 64)
  - Daily Traffic Flow on Selected Highways In Maryland & Washington Regional District map, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 65)
  - White Men's Roads Thru Black Men's Homes Poster With map, 1969 (Box 46, Folder 66)
- Series 11: Picket Signs and Posters
  - Posters (Box Map Case, Folder 1)
  - Posters (Box Map Case, Folder 2)
  - Posters (Box Map Case, Folder 3)
  - Picket signs (Box Map Case, Folder 4)
  - Picket signs (Box Map Case, Folder 5)
  - Picket signs (Box Map Case, Folder 6)
  - Picket signs (Box Map Case, Folder 7)
  - Picket signs (Box Map Case, Folder 8)
  - Picket signs (Box Map Case, Folder 9)
  - Picket signs (Box Map Case, Folder 10)
  - Picket signs (Box Map Case, Folder 11)
- Series 12: Charts and Graphs, ca. 1960
  - #1 in map case (Box Map Case, Folder 1)
  - Flip chart sheets and picket signs (Box Shelf, Folder 1)
  - Flip chart sheets and picket signs (Box Shelf, Folder 2)
  - Flip chart sheets and picket signs (Box Shelf, Folder 3)
  - Flip chart sheets and picket signs (Box Shelf, Folder 4)